Uli Siegmeier

UX Designer Uli.Siegmeier@gmail.com

Summary

UX Designer with a strong background in product management and computer science. I love sketching ideas, prototyping, testing and building them. I don't love graphic design.

As Head of UX and Product at Zoobe in Berlin, I designed, built, and maintained several apps with a small team. Before that I explored everything from physical computing and media installations to 3D visualization, stop motion animation and games. Currently happy doing hands-on research and prototyping again for startups and small projects.

Experience

May 2017 – now Lead UX and Product at BloodLink

Developing and testing minimal products in India for a social startup, based on research and stakeholder interviews in Denmark and India.

March 2017 – now Freelance UX and Service Designer Working with early-stage startups, doing user research, and developing and testing prototypes in small teams.

2012 - 2017 Head of Product and UX at Zoobe

Product strategy, management and UX design. Leading a small team of designers and working closely with stakeholders and developers.

2010 – 2012 Student worker Interaction Design at Nokia

Analysis and reporting of user feedback as part of the Consumer Insights team. Interaction design for Nokia Maps mobile app.

2010 - 2012 Interaction Design Research

Working on projects related to my Master thesis "Interfaces for Local Awareness in Urban Space".

2009 - 2011 Freelance Developer at lab binaer

Development for interactive media installations.

2007 - 2008 Frontend Developer at Northworks

Frontend Development for Goalunited, a browser based sports game.

Skills & Expertise

Design

- Prototyping (Paper, Mockups, Invision, Flinto, Proto.io)
- Interface Design (Sketch)
- · User Research
- User Testing
- Design Thinking
- · Information Architecture
- Animation (2D, Stop Motion, After Effects)

Product Management

- Agile Methodologies (Sprints, Backlogs, Trello)
- Analytics (Google Analytics, Localytics, Facebook, etc.)
- AppStore Management (Google Play, iTunes)

Development

- Physical Computing (Arduino, OSC)
- · Java & Android
- 3D Development (Processing, Game Engines)
- Python

Education

2010 - 2012	Interface Design, Master of Arts (MA), FH Potsdam
2005 - 2006	Multimedia Design, ESAD Caldas da Rainha, Portugal
2003 – 2009	Multimedia Design, Diplom Informatik (FH), FH Augsburg
2001	Abitur, Erasmus Grasser Gymnasium, München

Languages

German Native proficiency

English Full professional proficiency

Portuguese Elementary proficiency
French Elementary proficiency